<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>astro | Xueqing Chen</title><link>https://alphalyncis.github.io/tag/astro/</link><atom:link href="https://alphalyncis.github.io/tag/astro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>astro</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://alphalyncis.github.io/media/icon_hubb1969285a76d365392ed21399a12401_7090_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>astro</title><link>https://alphalyncis.github.io/tag/astro/</link></image><item><title>Observability of forming planets</title><link>https://alphalyncis.github.io/project/example/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alphalyncis.github.io/project/example/</guid><description>&lt;p>I worked on this project in the Computational Astrophysics group at ETH Zurich under the supervision of Prof. Judit Szulagyi. This project aims at bridging the gap between current 3D hydrodynamic simulation of planet-forming circumstellar disks with observations and understand how well we can observe forming planets and their circumplanetary disk with the next generation telescopes (with a focus on JWST, ELT and GMT). My work consists of three main steps: First, I post-processed the hydro simulations by JUPITER using the radiative transfer code RADMC-3D to create intensity images of the planet-forming disk. In order to do so I also helped in building a python pipeline to convert the JUPITER output and the simulation grid into RADMC-3D input formats, as well as writing hydro field visualization codes. Second, for each imaging instrument, I developed a pipeline for simulating its detector image with the intensity images from step 1 as the input source. For this, I used the python package Mirage for simulating JWST NIRCam and NIRISS, MIRISim for JWST MIRI, SimCADO and SimMETIS for ELT MICADO and METIS. Finally, I performed basic data reduction (i.e. with JWST pipeline) and photometry on the detector images to predict observed magnitudes and analyzed the trends with varying planet mass, inclination, etc. The extinction effect of the circumstellar and circumplanetary disks are also studied by including/excluding certain disk components in the previous 3-step method. The project resulted in a first-author paper, submitted to MNRAS.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>